Mss.Rec.146 Mss.Rec.146
American Philosophical Society
Nez Perce kinship terms
1988-1989
Mss.Rec.146
American Philosophical Society
20.0 Tape(s)
Linguistic field recordings of the Nez Percé language. Consists predominantly of elicitation sessions regarding Nez Percé kinships terms, adjectives, grammar, and number, with frequent intermixed discussion. Recorded by Shila Baksi with consultant Horace Axtell in Lewiston, Idaho from April 1988 to May 1989.
20 sound cassettes (19 hr., 42 min.): analog, 1 7/8 ips, stereo.
Axtell, Horace
Baksi, Shila
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Presented by Shila Baksi in 1990 (Acc. 1990-585r). This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Related Archival Material
Transcripts of these recordings are available in the Phillips Fund Collection (Mss.497.3.Am4).
Nez Percé Indians--Kinship; Nez Percé language; Nez Percé language--Adjectives; Nez Percé language--Grammar; Nez Percé language--Number; Sound recordings
- Audio recordings
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-04-21; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:27:29; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Scope and Contents note
    Original cassette 1A
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Audiocassette) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Lewiston (Idaho); Nez Percé Indians--Kinship; Nez Percé language
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-04-21; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:04; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 1B
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-04-21; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:54; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 2A
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-04-25; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:40; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 2B
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-04-25; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:12; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 3A
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-05-17; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:58; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 3B
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-05-17; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:52; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 4A
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-05-26; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:47; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 4B
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-05-26; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:35; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 5A
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-05-31; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:48; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 5B
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-05-31; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:34; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 6A
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-06-09; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:14; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 6B
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-06-09; 07-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:42; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 7A
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-06-09; 07-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:47; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 7B
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-06-14; 08-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:24; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 8A
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-06-14; 08-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:07; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 8B
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-06-21; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:58; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 9A
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-06-21; 09-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:57; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 9B
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-07-12; 10-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:49; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 10A
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-07-12; 10-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:07; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 10B
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-07-12; 11-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:55; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 11A
    Lewiston (Idaho); Nez Percé Indians--Kinship; Nez Percé language; Nez Percé language--Adjectives
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-07-12; 11-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:35; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 11B
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-07-19; 12-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:27:23; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 12A
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-07-26; 12-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:54; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 12B
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-07-26; 13-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:18:15; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 13A, part 1
    Lewiston (Idaho); Nez Percé language; Nez Percé language--Adjectives; Nez Percé language--Grammar
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-08-02; 13-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:12:19; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 13A, part 2
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-08-02; 13-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:09; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 13B, part 1
    Lewiston (Idaho); Nez Percé language; Nez Percé language--Adjectives; Nez Percé language--Grammar; Nez Percé language--Number
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-08-23; 13-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:42; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 13B, part 2
    Lewiston (Idaho); Nez Percé language; Nez Percé language--Grammar; Nez Percé language--Number
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-08-23; 14-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:01; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 14A
    Lewiston (Idaho); Nez Percé language; Nez Percé language--Number
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-08-23; 14-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:55; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 14B
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-12-06; 15-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:39; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 15A
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-12-06; 15-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:52; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 15B
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-12-27; 16-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:08; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 16A
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1988-12-27; 16-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:36; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 16B
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1989-03-13; 17-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:09; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 17A
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1989-03-13; 17-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:06; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 17B
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1989-04-19; 18-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:20; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 18A
    Lewiston (Idaho); Nez Percé Indians--Kinship; Nez Percé language; Nez Percé language--Mood; Nez Percé language--Tense
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1989-05-10; 18-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:40; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 18B
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1989-05-10; 19-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:56; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 19A
    Lewiston (Idaho); Nez Percé Indians--Kinship; Nez Percé language; Nez Percé language--Grammar
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1989-05-23; 19-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:56; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 19B
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1989-05-23; 20-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:50; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 20A
  - Nez Perce Kinship Terms, 1989-05-23; 20-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:00; Axtell, Horace; Baksi, Shila
    Original cassette 20B